extendedstayhotels.com 2019-04-05

# Extended Stay America - Privacy Policy

privacy overview   |   terms & conditions

Privacy Policy  
Last Updated November 10, 2018

1\. Introduction  
Extended Stay America, Inc. and its affiliates (collectively, “Extended Stay America”, “we”, “us” or “our”) own and operate this website. This Privacy Policy applies to www.extendedstayamerica.com and any other website linking to this Privacy Policy (each a “Site”) or software applications for use on or through computers and mobile devices (each an “App”) offered by us, which reference or link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the “Service”). We at Extended Stay America recognize that our users may have questions about the information we collect through the Service and how we use it. In order to address those questions, we have developed this Privacy Policy.  
By accessing and using the Service, you are acknowledging that you have read and understood this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with or consent to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please refrain from using the Service, or if you are already using the Service, please immediately discontinue your use of the Service.  
ESA Management LLC dictates the purpose for which your personal information is used and how we use your personal information.

2\. Types of Information Collected  
Information You Provide To Us  
Through the Service, we may collect personal information about you. Personal information describes information that is about you and from which you may be identifiable. Personal information relates to an individual consumer or business contact. We may collect the following personal information from you: name, address, telephone number, email address, and credit card or financial account information, depending on the service requested from us. We don’t require that you provide this information to us in order to view a Site or have access to its content. We may, however, collect personal information to process a reservation in our network of hotels, if you elect to participate in our hotel rewards program, or to participate in any other promotion made available online or through a mobile app to which this Privacy Policy applies. If you voluntarily sign up to be on our mailing list or create an account with us through the Service, or if you send us a message through the Service, or if you provide us with feedback, reviews or testimonials, we will collect personal information to fulfill or respond to your requests, for internal reporting, marketing, modeling and other benchmarking and business purposes. We may also collect personal information that you provide to us via our social media pages, including your social media account identifier and profile picture.  
When we collect payment information directly from you, like credit and debit card numbers and expiration dates, we transmit this payment data directly from you to the card processing company and it is not viewed or stored by us.  
Information We Collect About You  
We may also collect personal information about you through your use of the Service. This information includes online activity information and technical information about your usage activities, to the extent that such information constitutes personal information. Please also see additional information on our cookie usage in Section 4 below.  
We collect technical information that relates to such things as how many people visit a Site, which pages they access, the information they download, the type of browser and operating systems they use, the name of their internet service provider, device type used to access the Site (i.e., computer or mobile device), geographical data, the click path taken through the Site, use of features or applications on the Site, and other information of this general type. When you visit our Site we will automatically collect technical information and combine it with similar information collected about all other visitors to the Site. By collecting this information we learn how best to develop our Site to meet the needs and desires of our customers and visitors. We also collect this information for security purposes, to facilitate Site navigation, to personalize your experience while visiting the Site, to maintain and help diagnose problems with our Site, to build up marketing profiles, to aid strategic development and to help administer and audit usage of the Site.  
When you download and use an App, we and our service providers may track and collect App usage data, such as the date and time the App on your device accesses our servers and what information and files have been downloaded to the App based on your device number.  
When you use access our Service from a mobile device, we may collect information such as your unique device ID and your location information.  
Location Information  
We or our service providers may receive or infer information about your location from a variety of sources. For example, we may use your IP address to identify your general location or we may receive more precise location data from your mobile device (such as via GPS, wireless networks, cell towers, Wi-Fi access points). If you have enabled location information sharing while using the Site and/or the App actively or in the background, then your location information may be shared with our service provider in order to compare nearby offers. We may use location data to analyze certain information, and to improve our Service and relevance of the information we provide to you via the Service. Before we collect this information via the App, you must affirmatively opt-in to our use of such information and you will have the option of sharing your location at different intervals (for example, indefinitely or just for a certain period of time). Please note that if you do not share your location information then you may not be able to redeem certain offers and the App may have very limited functionality. We may use  
your location information to enable us to better focus or advertising and marketing efforts and to better tailor your use of the Service to your unique interests and needs.  
Information From Other Sources  
We may also receive information about you (including personal information) from third parties. For example, we may receive information about you from our affiliate marketers who refer you to us for services, or if you are on another website and you opt-in to receive information from us, that website will forward to us your email address and other information about you so that we may contact you as requested. We may combine the information we receive from these third parties with information we collect through our Site. In those cases, we will continue to apply this Privacy Policy to any personal information received pursuant to this Privacy Policy, unless we have disclosed otherwise.

3\. Methods of Information Collection  
As noted above, only technical information is collected from people who just visit the Site and do not take any further actions on the Site. Visitors who make reservations through the Site, email us, sign up for mailings, or otherwise communicate with us online will usually be required to provide personal information to us. Without this personal information, we would be unable to respond to your inquiries, purchase requests, and/or other requests. The same holds true when using the App to make reservations or otherwise communicate with us – if you request services from us through the App, you will usually be required to provide personal information to us.

4\. Cookies and “Passive” Collection of Information  
Whenever you visit or interact with a Site, we, as well as our service providers, may use assorted technologies that automatically or passively collect information about how the website is accessed and used, including by use of “cookies.” Cookies are pieces of information that are placed on an individual visitor’s hard drive for the purpose of keeping records. Cookies can enhance your online experience by personalizing your experience while visiting a particular website. We do use the cookie to help us identify website features and content which are of the greatest interest, so we will be able to enhance this website to provide you with a great web experience.  
You understand that you may have limited options with respect to your selection of cookie preference as we continue to update our Site and technology and cookies may not be able to be disabled. Please remember that cookies may help you take full advantage of the newest website features at this Site.  
Another tool that may be employed by us is a web beacon, pixel tag or similar technology, to which you must affirmatively opt-in. These tools help us determine various types of technical information. When you ask us to send you information on a promotion or via newsletters, web beacons may be used to determine how many of the emails sent were actually opened. Please note, however, that in general, most images viewed as part of a web page can be used as a web beacon. We are also likely to passively collect such other technical information as the IP address of your computer/mobile device and the type of browser that you are using.

5\. Do Not Track Requests; Third Party Tracking  
Certain web browsers allow consumers to enable "do not track" signals through which a consumer can signal to websites and online services whether the consumer approves of the collection of personal information about its online activities over time and across third-party websites and online services. Our Site does not change its behavior when receiving "Do Not Track" signals from browser software. Third parties, other than our vendors (such as our website analytics provider), do not have authorization from us to track which websites you visited prior to and after visiting our Site. That said, we cannot control third party tracking and there may be some third party tracking that occurs without our knowledge or consent.

6\. Questionnaires and Surveys  
Users of the Service may be asked to complete surveys or opinion polls regarding their interests, thoughts, opinions and attitudes. These types of surveys help us understand the needs and desires of our customers. Sample answers to such surveys may be posted to this website. Such sample answers could possibly include some of your personal information, such as your first name or city, but we will not include your last name, phone number, street address or email address as part of any publicly available posting of survey results.

7\. How Extended Stay America Uses Your Personal Information  
We use your personal information in connection with the provision of the Service to you. In particular, your personal information may be used by us, our employees, service providers, and disclosed to third parties for the following purposes.  
We use your personal information for the following purposes:  
 To communicate with you (including to respond to your requests) and other individuals and to enable you to take full advantage of travel-related opportunities, specials and promotions, which we may notify you about via email messages containing information about your travel and travel-related interests;  
 To provide you with the Service (e.g., booking services), including but not limited to, processing of booking requests, travel confirmation and updates and account management services;  
 To notify you about changes to the Service;  
 To audit and monitor the use of the Service;  
 To fulfill and complete your transactions, including using your sensitive billing information, such as name and credit number, in order to complete the travel bookings through our Service;  
 To measure interest and improve the features, content and quality of our Service;  
 To manage complaints, feedback and queries;  
 To improve our marketing and promotional efforts (such as conducting satisfaction surveys and analysis);  
 To provide you with information about our services and offerings (including details of any products which we believe may be of interest to you) in accordance with your preferences as  
indicated when you entered into any agreement with us, including any marketing consent preferences;  
 To comply with applicable laws and regulatory obligations (including in connection with a court order); and  
 To enforce or apply the agreements concerning you (including agreements between you and us).  
We may also use your personal information to assist in delivery of content that is customized to your interests. This type of customized content may eventually include such things as banners and hotel information. We do not collect personal information on an automatic basis, but we may combine technical information (which is automatically collected) with your previously submitted personal information.  
We may be required to obtain your personal information to comply with our legal requirements, to enable us to fulfill the terms of our contract with you or in preparation of us entering into a contract with you. For example, if you make a reservation or purchase through the Service, we use your personal information to set up your account and/or process your order. If you do not provide the relevant personal information to us, we may not be able to provide the Site, App or our Service to you.  
Where we rely on our legitimate business interests or those legitimate interests of a third party to justify the purposes for using your personal information, this will include:  
 pursuit of our commercial activities and objectives, or those of a third party;  
 compliance with applicable legal and regulatory obligations and any codes of conduct;  
 improvement and development of our business operations and service offering, or those of a third party; or  
 protection of our business, shareholders, employees and customers, or those of a third party.

8\. Advertising Partners  
We may deliver banner advertisements to other websites, either along with or through an advertising partner. If and when our Site chooses to work with an advertising partner for such a purpose, various forms of tracking may be used by said advertising partner(s). Please be sure to check the user agreements and privacy policies of any company serving banner advertisements, either on behalf of our Site or on behalf of any other website so advertised, should you be interested in the content of the policies governing their conduct.

9\. Disclosure of Information to Third Party Service Providers  
We during the course of our business use third-party companies and individuals to perform a variety of functions, including but not limited to, financial institutions that assist us with payment transactions and companies that assist to maintain the Service. We may disclose your personal information to third parties to protect the security and integrity of the Service, to correct technical problems and  
malfunctions in the Service, to technically process your information, to provide services requested, to help us market our services, to provide analytics or to take precautions against liability. We may also share information with our professional advisors (including lawyers and accountants) that assist us in carrying out our business activities. These third parties may have access to information, both personal and technical, that is collected through the Service. Such third-party providers are not to use the information to which they are granted access except for the purpose for which they were selected to work with us (or as required by law).

10\. Disclosure of Information to Other Third Parties  
We may use or disclose your personal information and other information we collect to the owners, managers and operators of our franchised hotels and owners of hotels that we manage but do not own that require access to your personal information for business purposes.  
We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you in connection with a sale, merger, consolidation, change in control, transfer of assets, bankruptcy or receivership, reorganization or liquidation of our business in which personal information would be transferred as one of the business assets of the company.  
We may disclose personal or technical information in cases where we believe in good faith that it is necessary to prevent a crime or an injury or financial loss to ourselves or to third parties. In addition, we may disclose any and all information required pursuant to a court order, subpoena or otherwise required by law, treaty or regulation or if requested by a law enforcement agency or government entity. We also may disclose your personal information to third parties if we have reason to believe that disclosing such information is necessary to conduct investigations of possible breaches of law, to cooperate in any legal investigation, or to identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who may be violating any agreement with us, including any terms of use for a Site or App. We may also disclose personal and technical information to third-party service providers, as described above.  
We may disclose personal or technical information about those people who contact us through the email features of the website or sign up for our mailing lists. There may also be times when we share aggregate information (that is not intended to individually identify any particular person) with advertisers, business partners, subsidiary companies, affiliated companies, parent corporations, sponsors, joint venture partners and other third parties in an effort to customize or enhance the content and advertising of our website for future users or to improve our marketing and promotional efforts. We may also integrate and aggregate data from web log files to assist us in understanding how the Service is used and the relative popularity of various features and content.

11\. Links to Other Sites  
Extended Stay America is only responsible for this Privacy Policy and the content of our Service. We are not responsible for the data collection and use practices and privacy policies on third-party websites that you may access from our Site or App. We do not guarantee the quality, content or availability of any third-party website to which a link may be provided. Any links are made available to you as a  
convenience, and you agree to use the links at your own risk. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our Service and to read the privacy statements of any other site that collects personal information.

12\. Participation by Children and Teens; Advisory  
WE DO NOT ALLOW INDIVIDUALS WHO WE KNOW ARE UNDER 16 TO PARTICIPATE IN OUR SERVICE. YOU MUST BE AT LEAST 16 YEARS OLD TO USE OUR SERVICE. IF YOU ARE BETWEEN 16 AND THE APPLICABLE AGE OF MAJORITY, PLEASE REVIEW THIS AGREEMENT WITH YOUR PARENT OR GUARDIAN. Please understand that we cannot necessarily tell if a user is providing us with his or her true age. If we become aware that we have unknowingly collected personal information from a child under the age of 16, we will make reasonable efforts to delete such information from our records right away.

13\. Access to Your Personal Information and “Opt Out” Procedures  
If you want to update or correct your contact information with us, please contact us using the telephone number or email at the end of this Privacy Policy. You may also use any “contact us” feature on www.extendedstayamerica.com or update contact information within any user account you maintain with us.  
You can choose whether or not to allow the App to collect and use real-time information about your device’s location through your device’s settings. You can manage these preferences when the App is first launched or at a later stage by using the setting on your mobile device. If you block the use of location information, the App may not function as intended and certain features may not be available to you.  
In order to begin receiving promotional email communications from us, you must affirmatively opt-in to receive these kinds of communications. If you elect to receive any promotional email communication from us, you will be given the option to “unsubscribe” from receiving further email communications from us if you wish to stop receiving these communications at any time, except with respect to emails relating to transactions (e.g., room or service bookings through the Service). Your option not to receive promotional and marketing material will not preclude us from corresponding with you, by email or otherwise, regarding your existing or past business relationships with us, and will not preclude us from accessing and viewing your personal information in the course of maintaining and improving the Service.

14\. Where We Will Transfer Your Personal Information  
We are headquartered in the United States and this website is intended for a United States audience. If you are located outside of the United States, be advised that any information you provide to us will be transferred to and stored in the United States and that, by submitting information to us, you explicitly authorize its transfer and storage within the United States. We will protect the privacy and security of personal information according to this Privacy Policy regardless of where it is processed or stored.

15\. How Long Will We Keep Your Personal Information  
We will retain your personal information for as long as is necessary for purposes for which it was collected. The precise period will depend on the reason why it was collected. Those periods are also based on the requirements of applicable data protection laws, applicable legal and regulatory requirements and periods relating to the commencement of legal actions.

16\. Your Rights  
The following is a summary of the data protection rights available to individuals in the European Union and the European Economic Area in connection with their personal information. Users located in certain countries including the European Economic Area, have certain statutory rights in relation to their personal data. Subject to any exemption provided by law, you may have the right to request access to such information, as well as to seek to update, delete or correct any such information. The rights may only apply in certain circumstances and are subject to certain exemptions. Please see the table below for a summary of your rights. You can exercise these rights using the contact details at the end of this Privacy Policy. Summary of your rights  
Right of access to your personal information  
You have the right to receive a copy of your personal information that we hold about you, subject to certain exemptions.  
Right to rectify your personal information  
You have the right to ask us to correct your personal information that we hold where it is incorrect or incomplete.  
Right to erasure of your personal information:  
You have the right to ask that your personal information be deleted in certain circumstances. For example (i) where your personal information is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise used; (ii) if you withdraw your consent and there is no other legal ground for which we rely on for the continued use of your personal information; (iii) if you object to the use of your personal information (as set out below); (iv) if we have used your personal information unlawfully; or (v) if your personal information needs to be erased to comply with a legal obligation.  
Right to restrict the use of your personal information  
Subject to applicable law, you have the right to suspend our use of your personal information in certain circumstances. For example (i) where you think your personal information is inaccurate and only for such period to enable us to verify the accuracy of your personal information; (ii) the use of your personal information is unlawful and you oppose the erasure of your personal information and request that it is suspended instead; (iii) we no longer need your personal information, but your personal information is required by you for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or (iv) you  
Summary of your rights  
have objected to the use of your personal information and we are verifying whether our grounds for the use of your personal information override your objection.  
Right to data portability  
You have the right to obtain your personal information in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and for it to be transferred to another organisation, where it is technically feasible. The right only applies where the use of your personal information is based on your consent or for the performance of a contract, and when the use of your personal information is carried out by automated (i.e. electronic) means.  
Right to object to the use of your personal information  
You have the right to object to the use of your personal information in certain circumstances. For example (i) where you have grounds relating to your particular situation and we use your personal information for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party); and (ii) if you object to the use of your personal information for direct marketing purposes.  
Right to withdraw consent  
You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time where we rely on consent to use your personal information.  
Right to complain to the relevant data protection authority  
You have the right to complain to the relevant data protection authority where you think we have not used your personal information in accordance with data protection law.

17\. Security  
Unfortunately, the transmission of information is not completely secure. We cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted to the Service and any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your personal information, we will use reasonable efforts to implement procedures and security features to try to help prevent unauthorized access. However, due to the nature of evolving technologies, we cannot provide, and expressly disclaim, any assurance that the information you provide us will remain free from loss, misuse, or alteration by third parties who, despite our efforts, obtain unauthorized access.

18\. Notice to California Residents  
If you are a California resident, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits you to request information regarding the disclosure of your personal information by Extended Stay America to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. If we change this policy, we will update this provision and provide instructions on how you may make a request for details. If any other state enacts a similar law as the California law, then this provision will also apply to such state. Nevertheless, if you wish to make  
such a request, please contact us or write us at 11525 North Community House Road, Charlotte, NC 28277.

19\. Changes to this Privacy Policy  
This Privacy Policy may be changed from time to time, so we encourage you to check this Privacy Policy when you use the Service. We will notify you of changes to this Privacy Policy by posting updated versions of this Privacy Policy on the Site and in the App. The updated Privacy Policy will take effect as soon as it has been updated or otherwise communicated to you. Your continued use of the Service following the changes to our Privacy Policy means you accept those changes. If you do not agree with our privacy practices as described in the revised version of the Privacy Policy, please do not continue to use our Site or App, as applicable, in any manner.

20\. How To Contact Us  
For privacy inquiries, please contact us or you may write our Data Protection Officer at 11525 North Community House Road, Ste. 100, Charlotte, NC 28277.
